Guide to the Mary E. Gawthorpe Papers TAM.275
Tamiment Library / Wagner Archives
- Series II: Correspondence
  - Pankhurst, Emmeline, 1908 (Box 3, Folder 108)
  - Pankhurst, Sylvia, 1929-1931 (Box 3, Folder 109)
  - Pankhurst, Sylvia, 1932-1935 (Box 3, Folder 110)
  - Paul, Alice, 1929-1931 (Box 3, Folder 111)
  - Penny, Frank, undated, 1915-1929 (Box 3, Folder 112)
  - Pethick-Lawrence, Emmeline, 1931-1935 (Box 3, Folder 113)
  - Pomeroy, Ella, undated, 1929-1932 (Box 3, Folder 114)
  - Post, Hermann, undated, 1932-1933 (Box 3, Folder 115)
  - R, undated, 1917-1933, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 116)
  - Reid, Helen Rogers, 1925-1931 (Box 3, Folder 117)
  - Reiner, Edith, 1929 (Box 3, Folder 118)
  - Rigby, Edith, undated, 1932-1951 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Robins, Elizabeth, 1931 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Rowe, Frances, 1917 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Russell, Ada, 1936-1944 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Russell, Bertrand, 1932, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Russell, Ethel, 1942-1945 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Russell, Hilda, 1920-1939 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Russell, Jessie, 1947-1951 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Russell, Marie Valentine, 1916-1927 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - S, undated, 1916-1933 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Sadow, Sue, 1932-1933 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Sanders, John, undated (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Sanders, John, 1921-1929 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Sanders, John, 1930-1939 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Sanders, John, 1940-1949 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Sanders, John, 1950-1959 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Sanders, John, 1960-1963 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Schulkind, Adelaide, 1929-1932 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Scott, Charles Prestwich, 1910, 1931 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Scudder, Vida D., 1932 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Sharp, Doris, 1931 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Shaw, George Bernard, 1912, 1933 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Shelby, Gertrude Mathews, 1921-1926 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Singleton, Caroline, 1926-1928 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Smith, B.A., 1915-1928 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Smith, Jessica, 1968-1969 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Stevens, Doris, 1928-1931 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Storm, Diana, 1928-1931 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Strang, Lewis C., 1927 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Sullivan, William L., 1921 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Swanwick, Helena, 1908, 1932 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Swayne, Blanche, 1932-1933 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - T, undated, 1919-1933 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Tolson, Chas. G., 1909 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Tone, Franchot, undated, 1930, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Tone, Gertrude Franchot, undated, 1919-1923 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Tone, Gertrude Franchot, 1924-1938 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Unity Society, 1929 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Upward, Allen, 1913 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Valiant, Grace, 1928-1930 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Verrall, Richard P. and Gertrude, 1919-1921 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - W, 1915-1931, 1966, 1970-1972 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Ward, Annie Gawthorpe, undated, 1913-1921, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Ward, Sidney John, 1910, 1929 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Ward, Stella Crossley, undated, 1930-1933 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Watson, Elizabeth, undated, 1926-1933 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - WEVD, undated, 1931 (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - White, Eliot, 1931-1933 (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Wiener, Paul Lester, 1929 (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - Woman Suffrage Party, Brooklyn, 1916 (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - Z, 1933 (Box 4, Folder 51)
- Series III: Subject Files
  - Actress Suffrage Organizations, 1909-1910 (Box 4, Folder 52)
  - Adult Suffrage Society, 1907 (Box 4, Folder 53)
  - Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America, 1920 (Box 4, Folder 54)
  - Artists' Suffrage League, undated (Box 4, Folder 55)
  - Bangs, Jean M., 1931-1933 (Box 4, Folder 56)
  - Biographical Materials: John Sanders, Jr., 1922-1933 (Box 4, Folder 57)
  - Biographical Materials: Mary Gawthorpe, 1881-1937 (Box 4, Folder 58)
  - Biographical Materials: Mary Gawthorpe, 1962-1990 (Box 4, Folder 59)
  - Blackwell, Alice Stone, 1916, 1947-1950 (Box 4, Folder 60)
  - Catt, Carrie Chapman: Speeches, 1911, 1916 (Box 4, Folder 61)
  - Central Society for Women's Suffrage, undated (Box 4, Folder 62)
  - Clippings: General, undated, 1912-1968 (Box 4, Folder 63)
  - Conciliation Committee for Women's Suffrage, 1910 (Box 4, Folder 64)
  - Davison, Emily Wilding, 1913 (Box 4, Folder 65)
  - Education Issues: Pamphlets, 1910-1913 (Box 4, Folder 66)
  - Ephemera: Programs, Invitations, Notes, undated, 1906-1938 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Fabian News, 1911-1912 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Fabian Society: Pamphlets, 1907-1912 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Family: General, undated, 1937, 1941 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Forcible Feeding: Clippings [See also Series VI, Box 10, Folder 14], 1912 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Forcible Feeding: Shaw Clippings, 1912 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Forcible Feeding Petition: Correspondence, 1912 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Forcible Feeding Petition: Organizing Materials, 1912 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Freewoman, undated (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Friends of India, 1932 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Garland, Charles: Clippings, undated, 1922-1929 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Garland Fund (American Fund for Public Service): Reports and Clippings, 1923-1934 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Garland, Marie Tudor: Clippings, undated, 1916-1931 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Hardie, Keir: Suffrage Pamphlets, undated, 1905 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Hunger Strike: Clippings, 1912-1913 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Hunger Strike: Correspondence, 1912 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Hunger Strike: Editorials, 1912-1913 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Hunger Strike: Letters to the Editor, 1912-1913 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Illness: Baylis House, undated, 1913 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Illness: Mary Gawthorpe Testimonial Fund, 1911 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Illness: Support from suffragists, 1915-1916 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Independent Labour Party: Pamphlets, undated, 1900-1906 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Independent Labour Party: Suffrage Materials, 1906 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - International Women's Franchise Club, undated, 1910 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Labour Organizations: Leaflets, undated, 1910 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Lancashire and Cheshire Women's Textile and Other Workers' Representation Committee, undated (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Leeds: General, 1906-1908 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Leeds Women's Suffrage Society, 1906 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Liberal Organizations, undated, 1907-1909 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Liberal Women's Suffrage League, undated (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Manchester: General, undated, 1908-1910 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Men's League for Opposing Women's Suffrage, ca.1909 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Men's League for Women's Suffrage, 1907-1909 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Men's suffrage organizations, undated, 1909-1911 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Merseles, Theodore F., 1929 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - National Committee to Promote the Break Up of the Poor Law, 1910 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - National Union of Societies for Equal Citizenship, 1923 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - National Union of Women Workers, 1908 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - National Union of Women's Suffrage Societies, undated, 1909 (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Nearing, Scott, 1916, 1931 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - New Freewoman, 1913 (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - New School for Social Research, 1930-1932 (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - New York, Journey to: MG, 1915-1916 (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - New York State Woman Suffrage Party, 1916 (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - North of England Society for Women's Suffrage, 1908-1909 (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - Old Time Players, 1929 (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - Pankhurst and Pethick-Lawrence Trial: Clippings, 1912 (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - Pankhurst, Sylvia, undated, 1931-1932 (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - Pankhurst, Sylvia: The Suffragette Movement, undated, 1931, 1936 (Box 5, Folder 49)
  - Pankhurst, Sylvia: The Suffragette Movement Correspondence, 1931-1932 (Box 5, Folder 50)
  - Pankhurst, Sylvia: Woodford Nursery School Committee, 1930 (Box 5, Folder 51)
  - Pankhursts: Clippings, undated, 1925-1932 (Box 5, Folder 52)
  - Parliamentary Debates, House of Commons, 1910 (Box 5, Folder 53)
  - Russells: Clippings, undated, 1914 (Box 5, Folder 54)
  - Sanders, John, Jr.: Condolence Cards, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 55)
  - Sanders, John, Jr.: Condolence Letters, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 56)
  - Sanders, John, Jr.: General, 1921-1922, 1934 (Box 5, Folder 57)
  - Scott, Charles Prestwich, 1929-1932 (Box 5, Folder 58)
  - Shaw, George Bernard, 1909, 1931 (Box 5, Folder 59)
  - Sims, George R.: "The Cry of the Children" (Tribune Extras Pamphlet), undated (Box 5, Folder 60)
  - Speaking Engagements: MG, 1907-1910, 1919 (Box 5, Folder 61)
  - Suffragette Fellowship, 1932, 1968-1972 (Box 5, Folder 62)
  - Suffragette Split: Clippings, 1912 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Suffragists' Vigilance League, 1909 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Sweated Industries Exhibition, 1906 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Union Francaise Pour le Suffrage des Femmes, 1909 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Upward, Allen, 1910, 1926 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Votes for Women, 1909 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - War Resisters' International, 1926 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Webb, Sidney and Beatrice: Course of Lectures, 1910-1911 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Women Writers' Suffrage League, undated (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Women's Freedom League, 1907-1909 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Women's International Matteotti Committee, 1932-1933 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Women's Labor League, 1905-1906 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Women's National Anti-Suffrage League, 1908 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Women's Social and Political Union, Aberdeen, 1908 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Women's Social and Political Union, Birmingham, undated, 1910 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Women's Social and Political Union, Bradford, undated, 1908 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Women's Social and Political Union, Dundee, 1908 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Women's Social and Political Union, Glasgow, 1910 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Women's Social and Political Union, Kensington, 1907-1911 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Women's Social and Political Union, Lambeth, undated (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Women's Social and Political Union, Leeds, undated, 1907-1908 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Women's Social and Political Union, Liverpool, 1909 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Women's Social and Political Union, Manchester, undated, 1908-1910 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Women's Social and Political Union, National, undated (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Women's Social and Political Union, National, 1906-1907 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Women's Social and Political Union, National, 1907-1908 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Women's Social and Political Union, National: Leaflets, 1909 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Women's Social and Political Union, National: Women's Exhibition, 1909 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Women's Social and Political Union, National, 1910-1911 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Women's Social and Political Union, Preston, 1908-1909 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Women's Social and Political Union, Rawtenstall, 1908 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Women's Social and Political Union, Scottish, 1908 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Women's Social and Political Union, Southport, 1908-1910 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Women's Social and Political Union, Wimbledon, 1908-1911 (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Women's Suffrage: Clippings, undated, 1908-1975 (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Women's Suffrage: Leaflets, undated, 1906-1911 (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Women's Suffrage: Pamphlets, undated, 1906-1914 (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Women's Suffrage: United States, 1916 (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - Women's Suffrage Crisis: Clippings, 1913 (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - Women's Suffrage Society: Blackpool and Fylde, 1909 (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - Writings: MG, 1908, 1912 (Box 6, Folder 41)
- Series IV: Educational Materials and Notes
  - Course Materials: London and Northern Tutorial College, ca.1890 (Box 6, Folder 42)
  - Italy: Notes and Materials, 1914-1915 (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - Notes: Miscellaneous, undated (Box 6, Folder 44)
  - Regulations for the Training of Teachers, 1913 (Box 6, Folder 45)
  - Secretarial Training: Kensington College, 1915 (Box 6, Folder 46)
  - Sketchbooks, undated, 1932 (Box 6, Folder 47)
  - Study Notes: History of the United States, 1916 (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - Teaching Materials, 1899 (Box 6, Folder 49)
  - Teaching Materials: Cockburn School, ca.1899 (Box 6, Folder 50)
  - Teaching Materials: Elementary Syllabus, 1903-1904 (Box 6, Folder 51)
  - Teaching Materials: Leeds School Board, 1898 (Box 6, Folder 52)
  - University of Kansas, 1916 (Box 6, Folder 53)
- Series V: Postcards
  - Postcards: Suffrage and General, 1903-1972 (Box 7)
- Series VI: Periodicals, Oversize Materials, Duplicate Leaflets and Clippings, and Artifacts
  - Anglo-Russian, 1908 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Cahiers Féministes, 1933 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Calling All Women, 1966-1967, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Calling All Women, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Equal Rights, 1931 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Freewoman: Nos. 1-3, 1911 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Freewoman: Nos. 4-6, 1911 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Freewoman: Nos. 7-9, 1912 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Freewoman: Nos. 10-12, 1912 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Freewoman: Nos. 13-15, 1912 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Freewoman: Nos. 16-18, 1912 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Freewoman: Nos. 19-21, 1912 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Freewoman: Nos. 22-24, 1912 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Freewoman: Nos. 25-26, 1912 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Labour Record, 1906 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Vote, 1931 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Votes for Women, Nov 1907 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Votes for Women, Dec 1907 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Votes for Women, Jan 1908 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Votes for Women, Apr 1908 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Votes for Women, May 1908 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Women's Franchise: Preliminary Issue, No. 1, 1907 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Women's Franchise: Nos. 2, 3, 5, 1907 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Women's Franchise: Nos. 7, 8, 10, 1907 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Women's Franchise: Nos. 31, 33, 34, 1908 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Women's Franchise: Nos. 35, 36, 38, 1908 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Woman's Journal: Nos. 13, 16, 1911 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Woman's Journal: Nos. 19-20, 1911 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Woman's Journal: Nos. 21-22, 1911 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Woman's Journal: Nos. 24-25, 1911 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Woman's Journal: Nos. 28-29, 1911 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Woman's Journal: Nos. 30-31, 1911 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Woman's Journal: Nos. 32-33, 1911 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Woman's Journal: Nos. 34-35, 1911 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Woman's Journal: Nos. 43-44, 1911 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Woman's Journal: No. 9, 1912 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Woman's Journal: Nos. 19-20, 1912 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Duplicate Leaflets and Clippings, undated, 1908-1931 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - National Women's Social and Political Union, National: Oversize Leaflets, 1908-1910 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Women's Suffrage: Oversize Materials, 1907 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Artifacts (not microfilmed), undated (Box 11)
  - Unprocessed Materials (Box 12)